To keep their sanity in an insane war, they had to be crazy.
The Boys in Company C is a war film directed by Sidney J. Furie.
Disheartened by futile combat, appalled by the corruption of their South Vietnamese ally, and constantly endangered
by the incompetence of their own company commander, the young men find a possible way out of the war.
They are told that if they purposely lose a soccer game against a South Vietnamese team, they
can spend the rest of their tour playing exhibition games behind the lines.
Pfc / Sgt. Tyrone Washington, played by Stan Shaw.
Pvt. Billy Ray Pike, played by Andrew Stevens.
Pvt. Alvin Foster / Narrator, played by James Canning.
Pvt. Vinnie Fazio, played by Michael Lembeck.
Pvt. Dave Bisbee, played by Craig Wasson.
Capt. Collins, played by Scott Hylands.
The Boys in Company C is a 1978 war film directed by Sidney J.
Furie about United States Marine Corps recruits preparing for duty
and their subsequent combat in the Vietnam War.
It stars Stan Shaw, Andrew Stevens, Craig Wasson and Michael Lembeck.
It was among the first Vietnam War films to appear after the
Vietnam Era, and was also the first role for R.
Lee Ermey of Full Metal Jacket fame.
It is the first in Furie's Vietnam War motion-picture trilogy,
followed by Under Heavy Fire (2001) and The Veteran (2006).
The film was a co-production of Golden Harvest and Columbia Pictures,
the latter originally handling theatrical distribution.
It was filmed in the Philippines.
Wasson plays guitar and sings the theme song "Here I Am",
used within the film and over the end credits.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam,
army, football (soccer), basic training.